Robert E. Sharer Papers
Robert E. Sharer Papers
1943-1971
Sharer, Robert E.
.75 linear ft.
The papers include correspondence, 1947-1952, articles, reports and other material on adult education by Sharer and others. Material on the Michigan State University adult education programs from 1944-1967 is included.
149578
Biographical History
Robert E. Sharer was chief of a division of the Michigan Department of Experimental Adult Education in the 1940's. Later he was Director, Office of Adult Education Programs in Continuing Educaticn (1958-63) and Director, Evening College (1963-68) at Michigan State University. He was Executive Director of the Adult Education Association of the U.S.A., 1968-70. Among his earlier posts, he was Vice-President, Adult Education, of the National Education Association.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert E. Sharer Papers extend from material from Sharer's years in the Michigan State adult education programs (1944-1967) such as correspondence, articles, reports and other material, to his writings (1948-1971).
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
In particular, see also the Adult Education Association (AEA) Records
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Sharer, Robert E.; Adult education -- United States.; Adult education -- Michigan.; Educators -- United States.; Evening and continuation schools -- United States.; Correspondence.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1947-1952 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Education 460, "Adult Education: General Survey," syllabus, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Adult Education Programs, 1944-1967 (Box 1)
  - Sharer Memorabilia, 1950-1963 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Addresses
    - 1948-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - Articles
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1949-1969 (Box 1)
    - "President's Column", 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Printed material, magazine format, 1960-1971 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Studies
    - "Adult Education in Urban American Public-School Systems"
      - Draft, tsc, 1952 (Box 1)
      - Questionnaires, [1952] (Box 1)
    - "A Michigan Integrated University Extension System", 1958 (Box 1)
    - "Trailblazers, Pioneers, Pacemakers and Builders", [ca. 1960] (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1957-1959; undated (Box 1)
- Writings by others
  - "Adult Education in the Public Schools and Teacher Training Institutions of Michigan", 1943 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State University Seminars on Leadership in Continuing Education, Reports and Proceedings
    - 1959 (2 copies) (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 2)
    - 1965 (Box 2)
    - 1966 (Box 2)
  - Montecito Workshop in Adult Education, Report and Proceedings, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Published Material, 1964 (Box 2)